foreign
[Music]
outside and as winter seeps away into
the watersheds and streams my garden has
been lying dormant for nearly half a
year however my hair has not and the
tangle of curls was in much need of a
trim
foreign
[Music]
I've never been someone who consistently
follows routine but I have found benefit
in having at least one to two nurturing
things I try to do each day recently I
spend anywhere from 1 to 20 minutes in
meditative peace with some soft music in
the background I used to do this with my
preschool students when I worked as a
teacher we would focus on relaxing our
entire body's limb to Limb and taking
deep breaths through our belly I do this
in the evening as well letting my mind
find a peaceful break from the day
doing this is not easy if you weren't
used to it but you can build up your
ability to sit in pure enjoyment to the
present and focus on your breathing and
full body relaxation
foreign
[Music]
each day I attempt to write down how I'm
feeling focusing on words of
encouragement in regards to whatever I'm
trying to accomplish addressing my
feelings of stress and speaking to
myself as if I was a loving friend
I try to shy away from planning out my
day in too much detail and only note
what truly needs to get done as for me
my Writing Practice must be a place for
encouragement and gentleness not a judge
of how productive the day was and a
reason to be disappointed if I'm not
efficient and instead celebrate taking
things slow if I've had a hard day I
write down encouraging words for the
next
[Music]
I have found them more consistent I am
in doing these things each day the more
my mind responds and trains itself ever
so slowly to seek out peace instead of
stress
I don't understand much about
neuroplasticity but it is worth reading
about I've been witness to the
transformation of my thoughts over the
last six months as I face the more
anxious side of my character and decided
that while I will always be sensitive
and feel deeply I no longer wish to be a
victim of my stress but instead learn to
manage it better and to thrive it has
been a long journey and very humbling
but I am so much happier and healthier
now and what I never thought was
possible has slowly come true
thank you
[Music]
I'm far from figuring things out I still
feel like a clueless student of the soul
but I hope I can offer some words of
encouragement there are some things we
cannot change but with each thing we
cannot there is something we can and by
believing it is possible we may slowly
leave our cocoons and transform into
something we never thought we could
isn't that exciting and what better time
to adopt a nurturing Pastime than in the
spring when everything is growing and
blooming alongside you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
this is the first time I've made cookies
with raspberry jam and I have to say
it's delicious these are supposed to be
a gift for my mother so I'm going to try
to restrain myself to one cookie since
the theme of today has been Alice in
Wonderland I admit that I feel quite
Royal and queenly eating these much like
the Queen of Hearts without the
homicidal instincts
which which I think is a good thing
[Music]
so often this month I found myself
standing here by my window just staring
out at the snow wondering that it's
still patient but still wondering when
the flowers will come this time last
year there was barely any snow on the
ground it's gotten to me a bit recently
I have so many things I want to do
outside and while you can do all sorts
of things out in the snow I love to
garden and all my pots and everything
are still under snow and I'm just so
impatient and I know that's not the best
but I also am so impatient to share all
my foraging and wild crafting as well as
Adventures out in the beauty of this
Valley and I do find it hard to film in
the winter because it's so cold and it's
much harder to bring my gear to places
but as you can see I've been keeping
myself quite entertained with baking
projects and home crafts this this year
for 2023 my morning routine and just
daily routines have changed drastically
I think in an attempt to deal with the
darkness and the cold of the winter that
was so long this year I have said in the
past that I don't regularly
meditate or journal and I don't do that
consistently but recently over this
winter I've just rediscovered a deep
passion for those pastimes meditating
from a spiritual perspective has been so
helpful to me and just aided me so much
in really learning on a new level how to
manage my anxiousness and I just feel
like I am slowly but surely becoming the
version of myself I always wanted to be
someone who still feels emotions and
still feels stress from the day from
work but they're not a victim of it
they're not a victim of this feelings
and that's something I've always wanted
to be able to be managing those feelings
in a way that I respect them and I
listen to them and I feel them but they
do not throw things in a chaotic
Direction in regards to my life I'm so
happy that I've been able to make so
much progress there oh I forgot to
mention
um I will be adding an extra bookmark to
my Etsy Shop sales this week if you are
interested I really appreciate the
support it helps keep this channel
running so thank you let me know if you
have any hobbies or past times that help
you through the winter and help keep
your spirits light I always love to hear
it and I hope you have a wonderful week
take care goodbye
[Music]
foreign